LUCAS SAECHAO

916-598-3485 | <u>lucasleechao@gmail.com</u> | 1129 Fallon Woods Way | Rio Linda, CA 95673 | <u>linkedin.com/in/lucassaechao</u> | <u>saechaol.com</u> | <u>hackerrank.com/saechaol</u>

OBJECTIVE

Passionate and learning computer science undergraduate with strong teamwork skills and a propensity for leadership, seeking to obtain a position in which I can leverage my four years of experience and education on both ends of the stack.

EDUCATION

California State University, Sacramento

August 2016 - May 2021

Bachelors of Science in Computer Science

• Concentration in Software Engineering

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

- Software Engineering
- Computing Theory and Programming Languages
- Database Management Systems
- Modeling and Experimental Design

- Data Structures and Algorithm Analysis
- Object-Oriented Graphics Programming
- Computer Architecture and Organization
- Computer Networks and Internet

TECHNICAL SKILLS SUMMARY

Languages: Java, C++, C, Swift, PHP 7.3, JavaScript, x86 Assembly, SQL, Verilog, HTML, CSS

Database Management: MySQL, PostgreSQL

Tools: Github, Docker, Maven, Eclipse, Atom, PHP Storm, Xdebug, VS Code, Xcode, Apache Server

Other Technologies and Frameworks: Drupal (Symfony), Google Cloud Platform, Microsoft Azure, Core ML, Create ML

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Drupal 8 Development Intern

May 2020 - Present

Divic.io - Sacramento, CA

- Developed and implemented website functionality such as dynamic form element updating, multiple windows targeting, and form validation on the front-end during a migration of the California Law Enforcement Website from Drupal 7 to Drupal 8 in JavaScript/jQuery.
- On the back-end, developed and maintained scalable PHP code, taking advantage of RESTful API for content filtering, user request processing and user login.
- Designed and deployed an algorithm that automated the migration of webform content and database submissions from Drupal 7 to Drupal 8 in PHP.

Front-End Web Development Intern

October 2019 - January 2020

California Department of Health Care Services - Sacramento, CA

- Front-end development position responsible for maintaining and ensuring active functionality and accessibility of website content, improving overall SEO
- Analyzed and developed strategies that enhanced and optimized web team's accessibility testing pipeline by over 60%.
- Audited and repaired potential accessibility issues, conforming every webpage to WCAG 2.0 compliance.

PROJECTS

Machine Learning Animal Recognizer

- Using Apple's CoreML, CreateML, and Vision frameworks, wrote and trained a machine-learning algorithm to recognize different drawings of animals.
- Machine-Learning model was trained using over 150 different drawings and images, and is able to deduce a hand drawn animal with accuracy.
- The applet itself was written in Swift and deployed to Swift Playgrounds as an educational Playground Book.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE AND LEADERSHIP

California-Nevada-Hawaii Circle K International

April 2018 - March 2019

District Technology Committee Software Engineer

- Worked closely with Technology Committee to perform and maintain the CNH Circle K district website.
- Planned and deployed tools that aimed to assist the efficacy of leadership at the club level.
- Shipped tool developed using Apache POI for Microsoft Excel in Java to automate data-entry and simplify data metrics and analytics to gauge club performance.